Here are some questions I thought of.
In general, I'm interested in what
variables are related to higher or
lower subway ridership.
If I were working for
the New York Subway,
this information might be useful when
scheduling how many trains to run.
But since I don't I'm just curious.
There are several variables that
could be related to subway ridership.
For example,
which stations have the most riders and
how dramatic is the difference?
I'd also like to know what are the
ridership patterns like over time?
Will I be able to see rush hour effects?
How will weekdays and weekends differ?
This data includes the month of May,
which includes Memorial Day, so
I wonder whether Memorial Day ridership
will be similar to weekend days?
I could also look at how the weather
affects subway ridership.
Do more or fewer people ride
the subway when it's raining,
when it's hotter out, etc.
I could also investigate weather
patterns in New York independently of
the subway.
For example,
since May comes before the summer,
is the weather systematically getting
hotter and hotter throughout the month?
And how does the weather
vary across the city?
Hopefully your excited to
answer some of these questions.
Lets get started.