Last lesson, you worked a lot
with one-dimensional data.
In this lesson, you're going to
work with two-dimensional data,
data with both rows and columns.
In pure Python without any libraries,
you might represent this
data using a list of lists.
So one list for the first row,
one list for the second row and so
on, and
then put each of those lists on a list.
In NumPy instead of creating
an array of arrays,
you can create a single
two-dimensional array.
In Pandas,
there's a different data structure for
two-dimensional data called a DataFrame.
Just like last lesson, I prefer to
use Pandas since it has additional
functionality, but I'm going to start
with NumPy because it's simpler.
So what's the difference between
making a single two-dimensional
array in NumPy Instead of making
a one-dimensional array whose
elements are also arrays?
One important difference is that
because of how NumPy is implemented,
making a single 2D array
is more memory efficient.
If you'd like to learn more about this,
follow the link in the instructor notes.
The syntax for accessing
elements is also a bit different.
Say you wanted to access the element
at row one and column three.
You would do this using
the code a[1,3] rather than
a[1][3] which is what you would do for
an array of arrays.
You can also make either the row
position, the column position or
both a slice,
rather than a single number
using the colon notation
you learned in last lesson.
Another difference is with the functions
you learned last lesson, mean,
standard deviation, and so on.
With a two dimensional array,
these functions will operate
on the entire array.
So in this case, mean would calculate
the mean of all these values,
ignoring which rows and
columns they were in.
You can't take the mean
of an array of arrays,
although you could take the mean
of each individual row.
On the next screen, you'll get
a chance to play around with using
an umpire array to
represent subway ridership.
Each row will be a different date, and
each column will be a different station.
Try out the example code
given to see what it does.
Then write a function that first finds
the station with the maximum riders on
the first day.
Then find the mean riders per day for
that station.
Also return the mean riders per day
across all stations for comparison.