First, I'm going to write code that will
work on this small example array, so
that I can see whether it's
working at every step.
Then when I'm finished, I'll turn it
into this function, mean riders for
max station.
The first step is to find the station
with the maximum riders on
the first day.
The first day is row 0 of the array,
which I can get by passing 0 as the row
position, and colon, meaning all of
the columns, as the column position.
And I"ll check that that worked and
sure enough, the first row was printed.
Now to find the maximum value,
I would find the .max function.
What I actually need is the station
that had the maximum value.
To get that,
I'll use the arg max function,
which will return the position
of the maximum value.
Taking a a look,
I can see it was position 3.
And sure enough, column 3 in
the array has the maximum value.
I'll name this value max_station.
Next I want to find the mean
riders per day for that station.
First I want to get the ridership
data for that station, so
I'll select all rows, and
the max_station column.
And I'll take a look, and sure enough,
that gives the correct column
of the ridership data.
Next I'll take the mean of those values.
And I'll call it mean_for_max, meaning
the mean value for the max station.
Finally, I need to find
the overall mean for comparison.
I can do that by simply
taking ridership.mean.
Now I'm ready to move this
code inside of my function.
Since the example array and the argument
to the function have the same name,
ridership, I don't need
to rename anything.
And I'll return both values.
Next I'll call this function
on the example array.
It looks like the overall mean
was about 2300 and the mean for
the max station was about 3200.
So the station with the higher
ridership on the first day
also had a higher ridership
overall than the average.
Of course, that doesn't mean it has
the maximum overall ridership out of
any station, but you'll calculate
that in the next exercise.