First, I want to find the mean ridership
per day for each subway station.
Since each station is a column,
I can do this using the mean
function with an axis of 0.
Sure enough, that gave me five means.
One for each of the subway
stations in this array.
I'll call this array station riders
since it contains the ridership for
each station.
Next, I need to find both the maximum
daily ridership and the minimum.
I can find the maximum by
taking station_riders.max and
the minimum by taking
station_riders.min.
Next I'll move this code inside
of my function, and again,
I don't need to change
any variable names.
And I'll return the max_daily_ridership,
and the min_daily_ridership.
Finally I'll run this function
on the example array.
It looks like the station with
the maximum riders per day had about
3200 and the station with
the minimum had about 1,000.
The maximum is the same value that we
saw last time as the mean ridership for
the station with the maximum
on the first day.
Which indicates that the station in
this case that had the most riders on
the first day also had
the most riders overall.
The minimum is lower than the overall
mean we saw before, which makes sense.