Once you've created a data frame,
how do you access its elements?
As an example, I'm using the same
ridership data that you looked at
earlier, with station
names as the column names.
I'll also use the index argument
to add dates, as the row indexes.
When I take a look at the data frame,
iPython notebook displays it as a table,
with the appropriate column names and
row indexes.
Accessing a single row of
a data frame is similar to
accessing a single element of a series.
You use .loc to access
rows by their indexes.
So here this code will give me
the second row of the data frame.
Similarly, you can use iloc to
access rows by position, so
this code gives me the last
row of the data frame.
To access a single element,
you can also use loc and iloc, but
this time,
indicating both a row and a column.
For example iloc at 0,
3 gives the element for row 0, column 3.
Similarly, using .loc I can
specify a date and a unit and
get the corresponding value for
that date and unit.
You can also access columns
using square brackets.
So this code gives me
the column just for
unit R006 and you can see
the beginning of that column here.
If this is starting to seem like
a lot to keep track of, don't worry,
it's all in the cheat sheet available
in the downloadable section.
You can also use .values to get a 2D
NumPy array containing only the values
from your data frame,
not the column names or row indexes.
Of course you'll have to be careful
of your data types if you do this.
One reason you might do this is if
you wanted to take the mean of all
the values, rather than the mean
of each row or each column.
That operation isn't supported for
Panda's data frames.
But you could call .mean on
the NumPy array using .values.
On the next screen you'll have a chance
to play around with data frames.
I also want you to get some practice
using data frames by re-writing
one of the functions you wrote earlier,
but this time for data frames.
You could just call .values and
then reuse the code that you wrote for
NumPy arrays.
But I recommend that you figure out
which of the operations you did before
will still work on data frames, and
which you'll have to use .values for.