I'll start with the same function I
wrote before for NumPy arrays, and
then I'll try each line to see whether
it works on data frames as well.
First I'll try out
the first line of code,
which is meant to take the argmax
of the first row in the data frame.
This gives me a pretty scary
looking error message,
starting with type error and
ending with unhashable type.
Now, it can be really hard to figure out
why you're getting error messages like
this, and
I find that in general Panda's error
messages aren't always very helpful.
Usually what I do is try to double
check the codes that I just wrote.
So for example, if I was modifying some
code from a documentation page, I'll
make sure that I used exactly the same
code as the documentation page used.
In this case,
the problem is that to access a row
of a dataframe, I need to use i loc.
I also don't need this colon
anymore to specify all columns.
And this time when I run
the code I get the value R006.
It looks like R006 is the fourth station
which is indeed the one with the maximum
riders on the first day.
Note that for a numpy array the arc
max function returned to the position.
But for a series, the arc max function
is returning the index of the series.
Or in this case the column
name from the data frame.
So I'll update this line
within my function.
Next I'll try out the second
line of code from the function.
I've used R006 here as the max station.
Again, I get a scary
looking error message and
again this is because this is not how
you access a column of a data frame.
I don't need the colon here.
So trying again it looks
like it worked this time.
I'll go ahead and make that
update in the function as well.
And finally I'll try out the last
line of code from the function.
And this line of code does work but
it provides a series containing
the mean for each column.
Rather than the overall mean,
which is what I wanted.
Like I mentioned before,
there's no way to directly calculate
the overall mean of the dataframe, so
instead I'll use .values to take
the mean of the NumPy array.
And trying this out, I can see that it
gives a single number, like I expected.
And once again, I'll update
the corresponding part of the function.
Now I'll try calling this function
on my ridership data frame and
I get the same answer that I got before
with an NumPy array, which is good.