In the following quiz, I'd like you to
write a function to calculate what's
called the correlation of two variables.
It's also known as Pearson's r.
In the previous lesson,
you used a rough heuristic to determine
how correlated two variables were.
For each pair of values, you looked
at whether both values were above
their respective means, both below,
or one above and one below.
The idea behind Pearson's r is similar.
First, you standardize each variable.
That is, convert it to a number
of standard deviations above or
below the mean.
Then, you multiply each pair of values
and take the average of the products.
So, r is equal to the average
of x in standard units,
times y in standard units.
Let's take a look at what this is doing.
First, by standardizing,
we're converting both
variables to a similar scale.
So for example, if the variables were
much more spread out in the y dimension
than in the x dimension,
then standardizing would spread the
variables out more in the x dimension.
Next, since the mean is
subtracted from each data point,
the area is essentially
divided into four quadrants.
Where both values are above the mean,
both values are below the mean, or
one value is above the mean and
the other is below.
If both values are above the mean,
then the standardized x value and
y value will both be positive, so
the product will be positive as well.
If both values are below the mean,
then the standardized x and
y coordinates will both be negative.
So again the product will be positive.
Thus is Pearson's r is positive,
then as one variable increases
the other tends to increase as well.
On the other hand,
if one value is below the mean, and
the other value is above the mean,
then the product will be negative.
So if Pearson's r is negative,
that means as one variable increases,
the other tends to decrease.
Pearson's r is more accurate than
the heuristic you used earlier,
since it takes into account more
information than just which quadrant
each data point lies in.
For example, this data point is very
close to the mean of the y values, so
the contribution to
Pearson's r will be small.
On the other hand, this data point
is very far from each of the means.
So the contribution to
Pearson's r will be large.
Pearson's r can range from -1 to +1.
If it is near zero, that means the
variables are not strongly correlated.
There's a link in the instructor
notes to a page with graphs for
different values of Pearson's r.
So that you can get a feel for
what different values of Pearson's
r look like in a scatter plot.
In the next exercise you're going to
write a function to compute Pearson's r.
Then you can use it to check some
different variables from the New York
subway data set, and
see how correlated they are.
When standardizing both x and y,
you'll need to pass the argument
ddof=0 to Panda's standard
deviation function.
This argument controls
whether the corrected or
the uncorrected standard
deviation is taken.
If you don't know what
the difference is,
there's more information on the page
linked in the instructor notes.
Many times when you're standardizing
variables, it doesnt matter too much
whether you take the corrected or
uncorrected standard deviation.
But to calculate Pearson's r
specifically, it's important to take
the uncorrected standard deviation,
which you can do using ddof=0.