To write this function, I'll first
need to standardize both x and y.
You've written code to standardize
a variable before, but
this time it's a little different
because you'll need to make sure you
take the uncorrected standard deviation
by passing ddof = 0 for both variables.
As before, I also need to be
careful about the parenthesis.
Then to multiply each pair of values,
I'll use times which does
vectorized multiplication.
Then I'll use mean to take the average
of the products, adding parentheses so
that I take the mean of the products
rather than just taking the mean
of y and then multiplying by x.
And I'll return this value.
NumPy actually has a function that will
calculate Pearson's r for you, but
it can be useful to write the code
yourself the first time so
that you'll understand what it's doing.
In the future though,
I'd recommend using NumPy's function
rather than writing your own.
Next, I'll use this function to
calculate the correlation between some
of the variables in the subway data.
First, I'll calculate the correlation
between entries and hourly, or
the number of entries each hour and mean
precipi or the mean precipitation for
the the day, and
I can see that the result is about 0.03.
This value is positive, which means
that when precipitation is higher,
subway ridership is higher as well.
But it's also very small,
which means that the relationship
isn't particularly strong.
For comparison, I'm going to take
the correlation between two variables
that I expect to be more
strongly correlated.
ENTRIESn_hourly is the number of people
who ride the subway each hour, and
ENTRIESn is a cumulative total of how
many people have ridden the subway
that increases each hour.
I definitely expect these two
variables to be correlated,
although I don't expect the relationship
to be super strong, necessarily,
since the total number of entries
depends on the number of entries for
all previous hours as well as all
the entries in the current hour.
But the result I get here is about 0.58,
which is much higher than for
entries in hourly and mean percipi but
is also much less than the maximum
value for Pearson's r, which is one.