Data frames also support
vectorized operations, and
they work similarly to vectorized
operations for 2D NumPy arrays.
Like pandaSeries, they match up
elements by index and column name,
rather than by position.
On the next screen you'll
get a chance to try out some
different vectorized operations and
see what they do.
There will also be an exercise for
you to get some practice.
The Subway data in its original
format did not include
the hourly entries and exits.
Instead, it had cumulative or
total entries and exits.
So, for example if the total
entries were 10, 40, 60,
65 and 85 for the first five
hours the station was open.
Then the hourly entries for
the first hour would be 10.
Again, assuming that this is
the first hour the station was open.
And the entries for
the next hour would be 30,
since 30 people joined to bring
the total from 10 up to 40.
And the rest of the hourly
values would be 20, 5, and 20.
We converted the total entries and
exits into the hourly entries and
exits that are available in the file
in the downloadable section.
In the following exercise you'll write a
function that takes in a data frame with
cumulative entries in one column and
cumulative exits in a second column.
And then return the data frame
with hourly entries and exits.
You might find the shift
function helpful.
Documentation for it is linked
in the instructor's notes but
I recommend that you just try it out and
see what it does.