I mentioned that the shift
function might be helpful.
So I'll start off by looking
at the documentation for that.
The documentation says that the function
will shift the index by the desired
number of periods with
an optional time frequency.
Now that seems pretty cryptic to me.
So, I'm just going to try the function
out and see what it does.
One thing I do see here,
is that the shift function needs to
take an argument called periods,
which is an integer indicating
the number of periods to move.
So, I'll try shifting the example
entries and exits data frame and
to start off with, I'll shift with
a number of periods equal to one.
When I try this out,
it looks like the first row of
the resulting DataFrame contains NaNs.
The second row corresponds to the first
row of the original DataFrame,
the third row corresponds to
the second row, and so on.
Just to make sure I understand, I've
also run this function with the argument
2, and
this time the first two rows are NaNs.
And the third row of the resulting data
frame corresponds to the first row of
the original data frame.
To calculate the hourly entries and
exits, I want to take each value in
the data frame and subtract
the value from the previous row,
which I can do using vectorized
operations and the shift function.
Here I've taken each value in
the data frame and subtracted,
that dataframe shifted by one,
which will give me the previous row.
When I run this function
on the example dataframe,
I get the following output,
which looks reasonable.
One odd thing is that the first
row contains NaNs, but
when you think about it,
this makes sense.
Because for the first row in the data
frame, you dont know how many hourly
entries and exits there were, since
there's no previous row to compare to.
It might make sense though to drop this
row or replace these values with zero.