Just like for a pandas series,
you sometimes might want to perform some
computation on a DataFrame that can't
be done using built-in functions or
operations.
Similarly to a series,
you can write a function, let's say f,
that takes in a single element from
the DataFrame and returns a new element.
Then you can apply
that function f to each
element of the original DataFrame
in order to get a new DataFrame.
For example, last lesson,
I wrote a function called clean_state
to take in a state that might
be in one format or another, and
return it in a standardized format.
To call this function on each
element of the DataFrame df,
you would call df.applymap(clean_state).
Now, why is this
function called applymap
instead of apply like it was for series?
I think it's kind of unfortunate, but
you'll see in the next video that apply
does something slightly different for
DataFrames.
In the next exercise, I want you
to write a function that converts
numerical grades to letter grades.
You'll be given a DataFrame
where each column is an exam,
each row is a student and each value is
the score that student got on that exam.
You should use the rule that
a score of 90 or higher is an A,
80 or higher is a B, and so on.
Use applymap to create a new DataFrame,
where each numerical score has
been replaced by a letter grade.