I mentioned in the last video that data
frames also have an apply function, so
what does it do?
Well, in some sense,
apply on data frames actually is
the direct analog of apply on a series.
It depends on what you consider
a single piece of a data frame.
You could say that a single piece is
a column, rather than a single element.
The function you pass to apply, which
I'll call f, takes in a panda series,
which is an entire column
of the data frame.
And it returns a new panda series,
which is a new column of the data frame.
Then when you call df.apply(f),
apply calls your function f on
each column of the data frame.
You might be wondering why you would
do this, instead of using apply map.
And the answer is that
the operation you want to do to
each element of the data frame
might depend on the entire column.
Consider the example
of grading on a curve.
Suppose I want to give an A to the 20%
of students with the highest grades,
B to the next 30%, C to 30%,
D to 10%, and F to 10%.
Let's not debate whether this
is a reasonable grading policy.
Instead, let's talk about
the code I would write.
I could store the numerical scores in
a data frame just like I did before,
with one exam in each column and
one student in each row.
But this time I can't use apply map.
If I just look at one score, I don't
know what letter grade it should get
without looking at the other scores for
that exam.
For example, is a score of 70 an A?
If the other scores on the exam are all
high, then 70 would not be an A.
But if the other scores on the exam are
all low because this was a harder exam,
than a 70 might be an A.
So what I would do is write a function
f that takes in the scores for
a single exam, and
returns converted scores for that exam.
Then I would call df.apply(f) to apply
that function to the entire data frame.
Apply also takes an access argument so
you can also write a function that
operates on one row at a time
if that's what you need.
Last lesson you wrote a function to
standardize a single panda series.
That is, convert each value to
the number of standard deviations
that value is above or below the mean.
Now, I'd like you to use apply to
standardize each column of a data frame.