In order to write
the standardized function,
I'm first going to write a function that
standardizes one column of a DataFrame,
which I can then call on each
column of the DataFrame.
I'll call the function that works on
a single column, standardized_column.
And hopefully, the code in this
function looks familiar by now.
I'll test this function by calling it on
a single column of the grades DataFrame.
And it looks good to me.
Then to standardize each column of
the data frame, I'll call df.apply and
pass in the standardized
column function.
When I try this out, I can see that
I got the same results as before for
the first column, and
the results for the second
column have also been computed.