There's also another possible way to
use the apply function for data frames.
Instead of taking in one column and
returning a new column,
the function f could take in one
column and return just a single value.
In this case,
instead of creating a new data frame,
apply will create a new series.
Where each column of the data frame
has been reduced to a single value.
For example, if I wanted to find
the maximum value in each column,
I could call, df.apply(np.max) to
call NumPy's max function on
each column of the data frame.
This would give me the same result, it's
called the built-in function df.max.
So in this case using the built-in
function would be simpler.
But as usual apply can be useful
when there's not a built-in
function that does what you want.
For example what if you wanted to find
the second largest value in each column?
In that case it would make sense
to use the apply function.
In the next exercise,
I want you to do just that.