I'm going to show writing the code on
this data frame of grades with two exams
and five students.
First, I know that I'm going to
need the mean of each column,
which I can get using grades_df.mean.
This gives me the mean for exam1 and
the mean for exam2 in a Pandas series.
I'll also take a look at
the original data frame here.
Now, in order to
standardize each column,
I want to subtract the mean of
each column from that column.
So I want to subtract the first mean
from every value in the first column,
and I want to subtract the second mean
from every value in the second column.
This works the same way you
saw addition just working.
I'll take grades_dr
minus grades_df.mean.
And sure enough, looking at
the first two scores for exam1,
I see a negative score for Andre since
his score was below the mean, and
a positive score for Barry since
his score was above the mean.
Next I need to divide each column by
its corresponding standard deviation,
which I can do in the same way.
I use grades_df.std to get the standard
deviation of each column, and
then I divide the data frame by the
series to divide each exam score by its
corresponding deviation.
As usual, watch out for the parentheses.
And running this again,
I can see that each exam has been
put in standard deviation units.
Notice that this code actually
looks exactly the same
as the code to standardize
a single series.
That's pretty cool, but as you'll see
in a minute, it's sort of deceptively
simple since standardizing each
row is a little more involved.
So how would I go about
standardizing each row?
Well, first I'll take a look at the
original data frame again for reference.
I know that this time I'll
need the mean of each row and
I can get that by using axis = columns.
Remember this means I'm taking
the mean along each column
which will give me the mean of each row.
And sure enough this gave me the mean
of each student across the two exams.
Now I need to subtract the first mean
from the first row of the data frame,
the second mean from the second row and
so on.
However, if I try to use grades df minus
grades_df.mean like I did a minute ago,
it will try to subtract the amount of
these values from one column of the data
frame which actually won't work since
the indexes of this series don't line up
with the column names of the data frame.
So I would just get a bunch of demands.
Instead, I'll need to use the sub
function which stands for subtract and
does the same thing as the minus sign
but it can also take an access argument.
In this case, the access should
be index since I want to match up
the elements of the series with elements
of the data frame using the row indexes.
And now I'll try this out.
Here I can see that all
the values in column one and
all the values of column two
have the same absolute value.
Which is what happens when you subtract
the mean from only two values.
I'll name this data frame
mean_diffs to use later.
Next, to divide by the standard
deviation I need very similar
code to before.
I'll take the standard deviation
of the grades column with axis
equals columns so that I get
the standard deviation of each row.
Then I'll use mean_diffs.div to
divide the mean_diffs data frame
by the standard deviations series.
And then I'll use axis='index' to match
up elements based on row indexes.
You can see here that
the results are the same for
each row, which again happens
because there's only two columns.
Now this code actually looks exactly
the same as the code to standardize each
column, except that each axis argument
was the opposite of the default.
This is something to watch out for
when writing Pandas code.
If you're doing a very common operation
then you likely won't need to specify
an axis since the default
axis will be correct for you.
On the other hand, if you're doing
something slightly unexpected
like standardizing each row instead
of each column of a data frame
then you're going to have to specify
non-default axes all over the place.