A lot of the questions I have
about the subway data set have
something in common.
For example, I'd like to look at how
ridership varies by hour of the day.
But the file contains many entries for
each hour of the day from different
days and different stations.
So first, I'll need to separate the data
into one group for each hour of the day,
then take the average ridership for each
hour, then I can analyze these numbers.
Similarly, I want to look at whether
rain affects subway ridership.
One possibility would be to
break the data into two groups,
data when it is raining and
data when it is not raining,
then I would compare ridership
between the two groups.
Again, there's a grouping step
followed by an aggregation step
where I sum up all the entries
within each group or
take the average of
the entries within each group.
I also said I was interested in
how the ridership varies by day of
the week where again,
I would need to group by the day of
the week then aggregate for each day.
This might remind you of the code for
lesson one where you grouped
data by account key and then added up
engagement records for each account key.
In lesson one, I chose to accomplish
the first step with a function name
group_data, and the second step with
a function named sum_grouped_items.
Pandas has similar built in functions
allowing this type of analysis to be
done with much less code.
Let's take a look at a concrete example,
suppose that I had the engagement data
for each student in a Pandas data frame.
I've created a small data frame
here to use as an example.
Then the code I would write to get
the average number of minutes spent in
the classroom would be
engagement_df.groupyby
('account_key').sum()['total_minutes_vi-
sited'].mean( ).
Now let's go through what each piece
of this code does one bit at a time.
First, calling
engagement_df.groupby('account_key')
creates a special type of object
called a DataFrameGroupBy object.
I think of it as being a dictionary
mapping each account key to a smaller
data frame containing only the rows
that match that account key.
Although, it's actually this custom
object rather than a dictionary.
If you want to, you can get a look at
the mapping using the .groups attribute.
This shows that the account key 1175
corresponds to rows 7 through 13 of
the original data frame.
And the account key 1200
corresponds to rows 0 through 6.
It's not usually necessary to directly
examine the underlying groups like this,
but sometimes, it can be useful to
get a sense of what's going on.
Next, I'll use the .sum
function on the group by object
to add up each column within each group.
You can see that this calculated
that the total minutes visited for
the account key 1175 was 2.7.
And the total for
the account key 1200 was 696.6.
Note that the date column is not
included in this output because it's not
possible to take the sum
of a bunch of dates.
But if there were other numerical
columns in the data frame,
they would be included here.
Now when I add at total_minutes_visited,
I get the same data back but this time,
it's in a Panda series.
Notice that before, this was in
a data frame with only one column,
which you can tell because it renders
as a table in the IPython Notebook.
Again, if there were more numerical
columns, they would show up in this data
frame, but this series will contain
only the total minutes visited column.
And now, since I want to take the
average across all students I add .mean.
And that gives me a single number, about
350 minutes for these two students.
Or perhaps even better,
I could use the describe function.
And then I'll get a bunch of
metrics including the mean,
standard deviation,
minimum, and maximum.
Now, the piece of this code that I found
most confusing when I first learned
about groupby was the sum function.
You've seen the sum function before but
that was for data frames.
This is a groupby object.
So, I wondered, what other functions
do groupby objects have available.
What if there is no function
that does what you want?
Well, similarly to series and
data frames, groupby objects have a lot
of convenient functions built in and
if the one you want isn't built in,
you can use apply and write your own.
In the following exercise,
I'd like you to group the subway
data by a variable of your choice,
maybe day of the week, hour of the day,
or whether it was raining.
Then find the mean subway ridership for
each different value, and
either produce a plot
showing the results, or
simply print out the numbers
if that makes more sense.