I'll use the function I wrote earlier
as a starting point since that will be
the code to calculate the hourly
entries and exits for a single group.
This time I've named
the functionhourly_for_group.
Now the first thing I'll need to do
is group the ridership_df by unit.
As usual this gives
the DataFrameGroupBy object.
Now it might seem logical to apply the
hourly_for_group function at this point.
However, if I try this I get
a message that says type error.
Unsupported operated types for minus.
String and string.
The reason this is happening is pandas
is trying to apply the hourly for
group function to each column of
the data frame, including the unit and
time columns.
Since these columns contain strings,
the function doesn't work on them.
You can't subtract
a string from a string.
To fix this,
I need to select just the entries and
exits columns,
before applying this function.
Once I've done that,
the function works as expected.
This time, I see two rows of NaNs,
one for each station.
That's because for
each station there was one row,
where there was no previous
row to compare it to.