So far in this lesson, you've worked
with just one data frame at a time.
However, it's often the case that
you'll have multiple data frames you'd
like to work with.
For example, in Lesson 1,
you had three CSVs.
So if you had been using Pandas,
you would have loaded them
into three data frames.
For example, suppose I wanted
to analyze how likely students
are to cancel once they've
submitted a project.
That would require information from
both the project submissions table and
the enrolments table.
I've only included a few columns from
each table to make the example easier.
Pandas has an operation called merge
that will allow me to combine the two
tables into one table.
This will create a new table with
all the columns from both tables.
Notice that there isn't enrollment
without a corresponding
project submission.
In this example, I'm only interested in
students who didn't submit a project, so
I'm not going to include that row.
You'll see how to do that in a minute.
So in the new table,
there will be one row for
each row in the submissions table.
And the columns corresponding to
the enrollments table will be matched up
by account key.
So the join date for
account key 1 was 5/11.
The join date for
account key 2 was 5/13, and so on.
Note that if there had been a duplicate
entry in the enrollment table, for
example two enrollments for
the account key 2,
then any projects submitted by the
account key 2 would also be duplicated.
So for the same project submission,
there would be one row for
the first enrollment, and
one row for the second enrollment.
For this reason it might be a good idea
to remove duplicates from the enrolments
table before performing the merge,
depending on your use case.
The code I would write to perform this
merge is submissions.merge(enrolments,
on='account_key', how='left').
The on='account_key' specifies how
to match up different rows from
the different tables.
So, in this case they were
matched by account key.
The how=left determines what
happens if some account keys
are present in one table but
not in the other for example this one.
The options for this argument
are inner right left and outer.
And in this case how=inner
would also have worked.
When you use inner, only rows with
an account key present in both tables
are kept, so this row was thrown out.
If how had been equal to right,
then rows from the right hand table
enrollments would have been kept,
even if there was no matching
entry in the submissions table.
Since there's no data for this account
key in the project submissions table,
NaN would have been filled for
those columns.
How equals left does the exact opposite.
If there are rows present in the left
table that are not present in the right
table, it keeps those rows.
In this case there aren't
any rows like that, so
left and inner do the same thing.
If you use outer, then all rows
from both tables are kept and
nans are filled if needed.
I've found that inner is the most common
kind of merge that I like to do, but
it really does depend on the example.
By the way, if you've used SQL,
you may recognize that a merge in Pandas
is very similar to a join in SQL.
If you haven't used sequel though,
don't worry about it.
Now, for the New York dataset,
the subway data,
and for the weather data were originally
gathered from separate sources.
In the following exercise I would
like you to use the merge function
to combine the two files
into a single data frame.
This will put the data in a similar
format that you've been using in
the lesson up until now.