I’ll start out by taking a look at the
first three rows of the two data frames
I want to merge.
The first thing I'll need to decide
is what to pass to the on keyword,
that is how to match up rows from
the two different data frames.
It looks to me like I’ll want
to match up by date and hour,
latitude and longitude.
And so I'll call subway_df.merge,
weather_df.
And then the on keyword will be
a list of those four fields.
I'll also need to decide whether how
should be inner, outer, left, or right,
and I've chosen inner, since I only want
rows that are present in both tables.
The result is a data frame with
all the columns from both tables.
For example, the entries and exits
columns are from the subway data, and
the fog and pressure columns
are from the weather data.
They've been matched up by date,
hour, latitude and longitude.
Now one thing that was convenient here
is that the four columns I wanted to
merge on have the same
name in both data frames.
What would I do if
that weren't the case?
For example, what would I do if
the date column were called DATEn
in the subway data and lowercase
date with no n in the weather data?
Because of this, Pandas allows
you to specify the left_on,
meaning the columns for the left table
and the right on meaning the columns for
the right table separately.
For the left on,
the columns will be the same as before.
And for the right on, the columns will
be the same but with the other name for
the date column.
And this code should give
the same results as before.