I decided to make a scatterplot of
subway stations with latitude and
longitude as the x and y axes,
and ridership as the bubble size.
The first thing I needed to do was group
the data by latitude and longitude, and
I also wanted to find the mean
ridership for each location.
And I'll just take a look at the first
few rows to make sure that it worked.
Now, this looks good, but
the next thing I'd like to do is get out
the latitudes and the longitudes
in order to make the scatter plot.
However, if I just add at latitude to
the end of this code, I'll get an error.
The reason is because latitude and
longitude are no longer
columns of the data frame.
Instead, they've been transformed into
the row indexes for the data frame.
I can prevent this by passing
as_index=False to the groupby function.
And now I'm able to get
out just the latitude or
similarly just the longitude.
I'll add the usual %pylab inline and
imports next.
And next I'll create the scatter plot
with latitude as the x coordinates and
longitude as the y coordinates.
Now I'll go ahead and take a look.
This worked to create a scatter plot
of all the subway stations, but
I haven't yet made the bubble
size dependent on the ridership.
I wasn't quite sure how to do this so
I decided to Google for
matplotlib scatterplot bubble size.
The first result here about
the plot marker size looks good.
Looking at the example code
here in the first answer,
it looks like I can give the argument
S to the scatter function.
And that argument can be in a array, so
that I can control the size
of each bubble separately.
So I'm going to try adding
the argument s to my code and
giving it the ENTRIESn_hourly column
to determine the size of each bubble.
Running this, it looks like it more or
less worked, but a lot of
the bubbles are huge, which is making
the plot really hard to understand.
To fix this, I'm going to create
a new variable called scaled_entries.
And to scale the hourly entries
I'll divide each value by
the standard deviation.
Next I'll change the size argument
to the scatter plot function to be
the scaled entries rather
than the raw entries.
And running this code the resulting
plot looks much more reasonable.
Now, the bubbles are maybe
a little small now, so
I could play around with
the scaling factor a bit.
But already I can see that there are
some areas of New York that tend to have
higher ridership.
Say down here and
maybe also up here a little bit.